NLP engineer

Summary

• Full name: Vadim Polulyakh

• Experience: 10 years

• City: Moscow

Core skills

Scala, SciPy, TensorFlow, Natural Language Processing, Natural Language Toolkit (NLTK), Akka, Play Framework, pandas, Apache Spark, Chatbot Development.

Projects

I have developed several projects from scratch, including projects for large companies such as Sberbank, Russian Railways, Rospechat. For example, this one: http://smartnalog.ru. This is a knowledge base on Russian tax law, developed by me from scratch in 3 months. The main challenge of the project was the development of a search engine. This search engine uses AI technologies (USE, ODQA) to select an article from text knowledge base. The question is forwarded to the lawyer if no article is found. Technological stack: python, typescript, tensorflow.

Publications

date	source	article name
2017	The NIPS '17 Competition: Building	Competition on Automatic Evaluation
2018	Intelligent Systems Radio Metrix	of Dialogue Quality Machine learning in
		law

Work history

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2017 - 2020	DeepPavlov	chief engineer	We were developing an open-source framework for building chatbots. Our framework includes state-of-the-art NLP models. I leaded the department of business solutions.
2015 - 2017	Raiffeisen Bank	senior lead developer	I was a developer engaged in the development of mission-critical services: authorization, monitoring, and
2012 - 2015	Edisoft Development ltd.	system architect	data storage. Head of the R&D department. I have prototyped several products, e.g. AlfaFactor- ing platform.

employment period	name of organization	position	duties/achievements
2011 — 2012	Acronis ltd.	software engineer	Participated in the development of Acronis Backup and Recovery for Linux as a regular developer. Moreover, I was a release manager and manage codebase of the Acronis Backup and Recovery project (~90GB in SVN repo).
2008 - 2010	Moscow Power Engineering Institute	developer	Participated in the development software for the Russian Ministry of Education.

Education

year of graduation	school	degree
2010 2011 2012 2013	Moscow Power Engineering Institute udacity.com Coursera.org udacity.com	Masters Degree in Computer Science Artificial Intelligence Software Engineering for SaaS Artificial Intelligence for Robotics
2014 2014 2017	Coursera.org Coursera.org HSE	Machine Learning Functional Programming Principles in Scala Masters Degree in Artificial Intelligence

About me

I am an experienced engineer who has created several large projects from scratch. I will be glad to help you if you need a rapid prototype of an AI-based web service, to solve a practical natural language processing task or to set up a machine learning pipeline.

Contacts

 $\bullet \ \ email: \ bavadim@gmail.com$

• web-site: bavadim.me

• github: github.com/bavadim